maccosmetics.co.uk 2016-05-26

# PRIVACY POLICY | MAC Cosmetics - Official Site

Effective Date: 01/05/2014

**M·A·C Cosmetics UK Privacy Policy**

M·A·C Cosmetics and Estée Lauder Cosmetics Limited (“we”, “us”, or “our”) respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you. This Privacy Policy describes the types of personal information we collect about our customers and M·A·C Pro members, how we use the information, with whom we share it, and the choices available to our customers regarding our use of the information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of the information and how our customers can contact us about our privacy practices.Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

Information We Collect  
Information You Provide  
How We Use the Information  
Information We Collect by Automated Means  
Technologies We Use  
Cookies, Web Server Logs and Web Beacons  
Third Party Web Analytics Services  
Targeted Advertising  
How We Use the Information Collected by Automated Means  
Information We Share  
Your Rights And Choices  
Data Transfers  
How We Protect Personal Information  
Links To Other Websites  
Updates to Our Privacy Policy  
How To Contact Us  

 **Information We Collect**

We may obtain personal information about you from various sources. We may collect this information when you provide it at one of our counters, stores, on our site, our social media platforms, our social networking or mobile applications, at one of our events, or when applying for membership in the M·A·C Pro Programme. When you visit this site, our social media platforms, or social networking or mobile applications, we may also collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons.

**Information You Provide**

You may choose to provide personal information to us in a number of ways, such as when you participate in an offer or promotion, or when you make a purchase on our site, at our counters or in our stores. The types of personal information you may provide to us includes: 

  * Contact information (such as name, postal address (including business address for the M·A·C Pro Programme), email address, and mobile or other phone number)
  * Age and date of birth
  * Gender
  * Username and password
  * Payment information (such as your payment card number, expiry date, delivery address, and billing address)
  * Your skincare concerns
  * Your professional status (for the M·A·C Pro Programme)
  * Contact information for friends or other people you would like us to contact
  * Content you provide (such as photographs, videos, reviews, articles and comments)
  * Information provided to us by social networks or mobile applications when you visit our social media platforms or use one of our social networking or mobile applications (such as your name, profile picture, likes, location, friend list and other information described in the social networking application sign-up page, or your geo-location details when using one of our mobile applications)

**How We Use the Information**

We may use the information you provide to: 

  * Send you promotional materials or other communications
  * Provide services to you
  * Process your payment and/or gift card transactions
  * Create and manage your online account, including administering the M·A·C Pro Programme
  * Respond to your enquiries (including requests and enquiries related to the M·A·C Pro Programme and your membership)
  * Communicate with you about, and administer your participation in, special events, prize promotions, programmes, surveys and other offers
  * Operate and communicate with you about our social networking or mobile applications
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; enhancing and improving our services; managing our communications; analysing our products; performing data analytics; and performing accounting, auditing and other internal functions)
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards and our policies

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection. 

**Information We Collect by Automated Means**

When you visit this site or our online advertisements, or use one of our social networking or mobile applications, we collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons.

**Technologies We Use**

**Cookies, Web Server Logs and Web Beacons**

Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings in your browser. Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our website.In conjunction with obtaining information through cookies, our web servers may log details such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone in which your device is located. The web server logs also may record information such as the address of the web page that linked you to our site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet.

To control which web servers collect this information, we may place tags on our web pages called "web beacons". These are computer instructions that link web pages to particular web servers and their cookies.

**Third Party Web Analytics Services**

We may use third party web analytics services on this site, our social media platforms, or our social networking or mobile applications, such as those of Coremetrics and Google Analytics. The service providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons to help us analyse how visitors use the site. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to these service providers, who use the information to evaluate use of the website. You may deactivate the ability of Coremetrics to analyse your browsing activities on this site. To learn more about Coremetrics, and exercise your choice with respect to their collection of information on this site, please click here. To disable the Google Analytics cookie, some browsers indicate when a cookie is being sent and allow you to decline cookies on a case-by-case basis.

**Targeted Advertising**

We also may contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information through the use of cookies, web server logs and web beacons on our websites and emails; on third-party websites and emails; and on our advertising placed on third-party websites. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests (including for companies not affiliated with us). You may see these advertisements on our websites and other websites. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. To learn more about these and other advertising networks and their opt-out instructions, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**How We Use the Information Collected by Automated Means**

We may use the information collected through automated means on this site to deliver personalised content, for market research, data analytics and system administration purposes, such as to determine whether you've visited us before or are new to the site, and for compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures, including compliance with relevant industry standards and the enforcement of our Terms and Conditions. We also may use the information in other ways for which specific notice is provided at the time of collection.

**Information We Share**

We do not rent lists, sell or otherwise disclose personal information we collect about you, except as described here. We may share your personal information with: 

  * Our affiliates within the M·A·C Cosmetics umbrella of companies for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.
  * Service providers who perform services on our behalf based on our instructions. We do not authorise these service providers to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. Examples of these service providers include entities that process credit card payments, fulfil orders, and provide web hosting and marketing services.
  * Other third parties with your consent (e.g., some of our Facebook applications may share information collected through those applications with your Facebook friends or other Facebook users).

In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal activity. 

We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your personal information with any enquiries concerning the processing of that information.

**Your Rights and Choices**

We offer you certain choices in connection with the personal information we collect from you, such as how we use the information and how we communicate with you. To update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit a request, please contact us as specified below. 

**Email Opt-Out**

You can at any time tell us not to send you marketing communications by email by clicking on the unsubscribe link within the marketing emails you receive from us or by contacting us as indicated below. You also may opt out of receiving marketing emails from M·A·C Cosmetics UK by clicking here.

You may opt out of receiving email communications by emailing [info@maccosmetics.co.uk](mailto:info@maccosmetics.co.uk). You may also opt out of receiving M·A·C Pro communications by email and that are not necessary to provide customer service by emailing M·A·C Pro membership at: [promembership@maccosmetics.co.uk](mailto:promembership@maccosmetics.co.uk) or by accessing the "Account Profile" section of the M·A·C Pro segment of the site which includes an unsubscribe option.

**Postal Mail Opt-Out**

You can ask M·A·C Cosmetics UK to stop sending you marketing communications by postal mail by following the instructions that may be included in a particular promotion. You also can request that we refrain from sending you promotional postal mail by contacting us as indicated below.

Please note that all M·A·C Pro members must consent to receiving communications via postal mail as a condition of their membership.

**Social Networking Application Opt-Out**

To remove or delete our apps from your social networking account, follow the instructions from the social network:

Facebook: [Link](https://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=170585223002660) provided by the Facebook Help Center.

**Geo-Location Information through Mobile Applications**

When you use one of our mobile applications, you may be asked for your geo-location. You may choose not to share your geo-location details by adjusting your mobile device's location services settings. To decline from sharing your geo-location details, follow the instructions on your mobile device on changing the relevant settings; otherwise, please contact your service provider or device manufacturer.

**Withdrawing Consent**

You may withdraw any consent you previously provided to us, or object at any time on legitimate grounds, to the processing of your personal information. We will consider your request and, as required by applicable, apply your preferences going forward, within a reasonable amount of time. Even where you withdraw your consent, we may still process your personal data for limited purposes, for example, to give effect to your request, or to safeguard our business. In some circumstances, withdrawing your consent to our use or disclosure of your personal information will mean that you cannot take advantage of some of our products or services.

**Reviewing, Updating and Modifying Personal Information**

Subject to applicable law, you may have the right to request access to and receive details about the personal information we maintain about you, update and correct inaccuracies in your personal data, and have the information blocked or deleted, as appropriate. The right to access personal information may be limited in some circumstances by local law requirements. You may request to review, change or delete your personal information by sending an email to [info@maccosmetics.co.uk](mailto:info@maccosmetics.co.uk) or for Pro Members [promembership@maccosmetics.co.uk](mailto:promembership@maccosmetics.co.uk)

M·A·C Pro members may also update their information by contacting:  
Constellation House  
3 Kites Croft Business Park  
Warsash Road  
Fareham  
PO14 4FL  
(0) 870 034 2676

Please note that M·A·C Pro members will be asked for identification so that we can assure you are the individual making the request with respect to your personal information.

**Data Transfers**

We may transfer the personal information we collect about you to countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**How We Protect Personal Information**

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorised destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

**Links To Other Websites**

Our website may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. These websites may operate independently from us. Linked sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. To the extent any linked websites you visit are not owned or controlled by us, we are not responsible for the sites' content, any use of the sites, or the privacy practices of the sites.

**Updates To Our Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. We will post a prominent notice on our website to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the top of the Policy when it was most recently updated.

**How To Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by email, telephone or write to us. For more information click here. 

Pro Members may contact by the following methods:

Postal Mail: For membership purchase or renewal or for Programme information, you may write to:

M·A·C PRO COVENT GARDEN  
27 James Street  
Covent Garden  
London  
WC2E 8PA  
0870 192 5185

OR

M·A·C PRO SOHO  
28 Fouberts Place  
West Soho  
London  
W1F 7PR  
0870 192 5555

OR

M·A·C PRO Membership Programme  
Constellation House  
3 Kites Croft Business Park  
Warsash Road  
Fareham  
PO14 4FL  
M·A·C Pro Membership Enquiries

Email: For Program information, please write to [promembership@maccosmetics.co.uk](mailto:promembership@maccosmetics.co.uk)

Telephone: You may also contact M·A·C PRO by phone:   
For membership purchase or renewal: 0) 800 054 2676   
For Programme information: 0) 800 054 2676 

Copyright © Make-up Art Cosmetics Inc. All worldwide rights reserved.
